How much pocket money did you get as a child, if any?
你小时候有多少零花钱（如果有的话）？
Was it a regular, weekly allowance, or just occasional one-off payments for chores?
是每周固定的零用钱，还是偶尔为家务一次性支付的报酬？
Parents around the world have different ideas about the dos and don'ts of pocket money.
世界各地的父母对于零花钱的宜忌有不同的看法。
How much should parents give?
父母应该给多少？
Should they track what their children spend money on?
他们应该跟踪孩子把钱花在什么地方吗？
And where is the balance between teaching children valuable life lessons and simply spoiling them?
在教育孩子宝贵的人生经验和单纯地宠坏他们之间，如何平衡？
Giving children pocket money offers more than just disposable income – it can provide lessons in financial literacy.
给孩子零花钱不仅仅是提供可支配收入那么简单——它还可以教导金融知识。
One of the first things children can learn is that money is finite – once it is spent, there's no more until the next allowance.
孩子们可以学到的第一件事是，钱是有限的——一旦花掉，下次发零花钱之前就没有了。
This awareness can help children learn how to budget and make good financial decisions.
这种意识可以帮助孩子学会如何预算并做出好的财务决策。
For example, they might spend weeks saving up for something big and exciting, rather than spending small amounts immediately.
例如，他们可能会花数周时间攒钱买一件大而令人兴奋的东西，而不是立即花掉小钱。
Making money mistakes while the amounts are relatively small can prepare children for when they start handling larger sums of money as adults.
在金额相对较小的时候犯财务错误，可以为孩子们将来成年后开始处理更大金额的钱做准备。
Some parents link pocket money to household chores, teaching kids that hard work and good behaviour is rewarded.
一些父母将零花钱与家务劳动联系起来，教导孩子努力工作和良好行为会得到奖励。
Louise Hill is the CEO of GoHenry – a money management service for children.
路易丝·希尔是GoHenry（一个面向儿童的理财服务）的首席执行官。
She says that earning through chores encourages financial independence and "ultimately gives much more satisfaction rather than instant gratification".
她说，通过做家务赚钱可以鼓励财务独立，并且"最终带来更多的满足感，而不是即时满足"。
The downside of this, however, is that kids may only help around the house when they receive payment, rather than seeing it as their shared responsibility.
然而，这样做的缺点是，孩子们可能只有在收到报酬时才会帮忙做家务，而不是将其视为他们的共同责任。
In their adolescence, young people may transition to a more lucrative way of earning pocket money – part-time work such as babysitting.
在青春期，年轻人可能会过渡到更赚钱的零花钱方式——诸如照看小孩之类的兼职工作。
Pocket money used to mean exactly that – coins or notes that children could keep in their pocket.
零花钱过去正是字面意思——孩子们可以放在口袋里的硬币或纸币。
And when they're young, seeing physical cash is a good way for them to understand money.
在他们小时候，看到实体现金是他们理解金钱的好方法。
But in today's digital world, families are increasingly going cashless.
但在当今的数字世界中，家庭越来越多地走向无现金化。
Online money management services are emerging in the market, many of them offering a combination of prepaid debit cards and an app that both child and parent can use to track spending.
在线理财服务正在市场上涌现，其中许多提供预付借记卡和一个孩子和父母都可以用来跟踪支出的应用程序。
Some even offer gamified money lessons and the option to set up pots to fulfil savings goals.
有些甚至提供游戏化的理财课程，还可以选择设立储蓄罐来实现储蓄目标。
This modern approach is just another way children can be prepared for adult life, where many transactions are digital.
这种现代方法只是让孩子们为成年生活做好准备的另一种方式，因为那时许多交易都是数字化的。
There's no perfect formula when it comes to pocket money, and a lot will depend on family situation and finances.
关于零花钱，没有完美的公式，很多事情取决于家庭情况和财务状况。
Ultimately, learning to spend wisely, save and even give generously can help children build a healthy relationship with money that can continue into adulthood.
最终，学会明智地消费、储蓄甚至慷慨地给予，可以帮助孩子们与金钱建立健康的关系，这种关系可以持续到成年。